Aaron Apple

303 Ilchester Avenue – Baltimore MD, 21218 (847) 970-0924 • apple@cogsci.jhu.edu • aaronapple.github.io/

Profile

Recent graduate of the Department of Cognitive Science at Johns Hopkins University, with expertise in human development and linguistics, data analysis, and visualization, with 4+ years of experience in research coordination, looking to apply my diverse research skills to problems in the applied social sciences.

Education

Johns Hopkins University

Baltimore, MD

Masters of Arts in Cognitive Science.

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Advisors: Drs. Akira Omaki, Kyle Rawlins & Geraldine Legendre

Chicago, IL

Linguistics Society of America *Graduate of the 2015 LSA Summer Institute at the University of Chicago*

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2015

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelors of Arts in Language and Mind, Minor in Creative Writing

Aug. 2008 - Dec. 2012

Skills

Research: Experimental design; Quantitative analysis; Data visualization; Scientific writing; Public speaking; Grant editing; Data management; Research coordination

Programming languages: R; Python; MATLAB

 $\textbf{Software} \colon \text{Microsoft Office}; \text{Adobe Creative Cloud}; \text{SPSS}; \text{Tableau}; \text{FileMaker Pro}; \text{Audacity}; \text{SR Research Experiment}$

Builder & Data Viewer

Statistical & Experimental Methods: ANOVA; Mixed-effects regression; Bayesian inference; Neural networks; Question answering; Preferential looking; Visual-world eye-tracking; Eye-tracking during reading; Self-paced reading

Languages: English (native); French (proficient)

Professional Experience

Manager of the Language Processing and Development Lab

Baltimore, MD

PI: Dr. Akira Omaki, Department of Cognitive Science, The Johns Hopkins University.

Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2015

- o Developed pipelines to manage, analyze, and visualize data for 12 experiments.
- Designed two experiments on child and adult language processing.
- Wrote five articles submitted to peer-reviewed journals.
- o Presented my findings at two conferences.
- Edited NSF grant application for a project on child sentence processing and executive control.
- Managed IRB protocols.
- Supervised five research assistants on four research projects.
- Conducted literature reviews for 7 experiments.
- o Wrote, designed, and edited newsletter presenting findings from 8 experiments for laypeople.

Research Assistant in the Davachi Memory Lab

Research Assistant in the Neurolinguistics Lab

New York, NY

PI: Dr. Lila Davachi, Department of Psychology, New York University.

May 2012 - Dec. 2012

• Assisted in designing and coding MEG experiment on memory reactivation.

• Managed participant recruitment and data collection for two fMRI experiments.

Research Assistant in the Consciousness and Computation Lab

New York, NY

PI: Dr. Hakwan Lau, Department of Psychology, Columbia University.

May 2012 - Dec. 2012

• Designed and coded behavioral experiment on dynamic control of memory and attention.

• Managed participant recruitment and data collection for three behavioral experiments.

New York, NY

PI: Dr. Liina Pylkkänen, Department of Linguistics, New York University.

Sept. 2011 - April 2012

• Designed and coded MEG experiment on domain generality of semantic processing.

Editorial Intern at DVL Seigenthaler PR

Chicago, IL

• Wrote twelve press releases for three business clients.

- Aug. 2010 Dec. 2010
- o Copy edited press releases and outreach magazines for two philanthropic clients.

Intern at 826CHI Chicago, IL

• Administrated the after-school tutoring program of 30 children and tutors.

Aug. 2010 - Dec. 2010

• Taught writing as a teaching assistant in two English classes in a Chicago public high school.

New York, NY

Research Assistant for Syntactic Structures of The Worlds Languages PI: Dr. Chris Collins, Department of Linguistics, New York University.

Jan. 2009 - June 2009

• Developed program to visualize featural and phylogenetic relationships between languages.

Publications, Presentations and Awards

Atkinson, E., **Apple**, **A.**, Omaki, A. (2016). Similarity of Wh-Phrases and Acceptability Variation in Wh-Islands. *Frontiers in Psychology*, 6.

Omaki, A, Lau, E. F., Davidson White, I., Dakan, M., **Apple, A.**, & Phillips, C. (2015). Hyper-active gap filling. *Frontiers in Psychology*, 6.

Apple, A. & Omaki, A. (2015). Incrementality and garden-path recovery in children's resolution of direct object vs. sentential complement ambiguity. Paper presented at the *Boston University Conference on Language Development, November 13*, 2015.

Apple, A. & Omaki, A. (2015). Development of sentential complement ambiguity processing. Poster presented at the *CUNY 2015 Conference on Sentence Processing, March 21*.

Omaki, A. & **Apple**, **A.** (2014). Adaptation of active gap filling in coordinated sentences. Talk presented at the *AMLaP* 2014, *September 4*.

Apple, A., Bemis, D., Marcus, G., Pylkkänen, L. (2012). Domain General Compositional Processing: An MEG Study. *Dean's Undergraduate Research Fund*, NYU. Poster presented at the Dean's Undergraduate Research conference and grant recipient of the highest award, \$1000.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). The role of incremental parsing on Japanese infants' word learning.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). Japanese infants' abstract knowledge of word order.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). Filler-gap processing in coordinate structures.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). Incrementality and garden-path recovery in child resolution of complement ambiguity.

Volunteering

Harwood Community Association

Baltimore, MD

Volunteer and organizer

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Harwood's 2016 National Night Out Against Crime: Solicited food donations from local businesses, ran the BBQ grill, and assisted in managing other volunteers.
- The 2015 Ilchester Back to School Block Party: Solicited school supplies donations from local businesses and assisted in managing other volunteers.